# KARINA MACANCELA

GITHUB LINKEDIN WEBSITE

github.com/kmacancela | linkedin.com/in/kmacancela | kmacancela.github.io

## **PROFILE**

I am a Full-Stack Developer with 2+ years of experience in building Java applications. I am adept at handling strict timelines while maintaining rapport with other developers in a Scrum/Agile environment to fulfill requirements. Besides Java, I have worked with various technologies including Spring, Bootstrap, Hibernate, SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Swift. In addition to development, I have experience in project management and have worked with various capability patterns, DevOps, and the business/financial aspects of projects.

### **EXPERIENCE**

SENIOR ASSOCIATE, INFOSYS LIMITED; U.S.A. - 04/2017 - PRESENT

I have been working closely with clients on-site as a software engineer consultant. I worked with well-known health insurance company, Aetna, for two years as a software developer and project manager. This allowed me to get experience in developing and managing projects from start to finish. I was trained extensively in both roles. Meanwhile, I continuously communicate and organize with our offshore team.

ASSOCIATE PROJECT MANAGER; AETNA; HARTFORD, CT - 02/2018 - 05/2019

I coordinated with project managers and stakeholders to track project scope, schedule, and cost. Assisted Project Managers in preparing the project financials such as labor and non-labor budget reports, major milestones, and forecasting reports. I performed activities such as creating audit records, validating approvals, and conducting compliance audits. Some project management tools I used were IBM Rational ClearQuest and ClearCase, Intuit QuickBase, PlanView, and SAP BI Launchpad.

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPER, AETNA; HARTFORD, CT – 06/2017 - 02/2018 I developed, tested, and supported various APIs for consumers and their requirements using IBM API Connect. I utilized Splunk to check logs for errors in order to debug API failures. Additionally, I worked closely with the DevOps team to create an automated and faster way to deploy APIs. I coordinated with offshore talent to gather requirements from consumers for API development. I utilized Git to upload completed APIs to the companies' private repository so the DevOps team could automate its deployment into testing environments.

FULL STACK DEVELOPER, REVATURE; FLUSHING, NY – 11/2016 - 04/2017 I used HTTP Servlet to handle GET and POST requests. I created a Business Delegate to build a bridge between business logic and backend code. I incorporated POJO Java beans to work with a SQL

relational database. I also used JDBC to allow clients to access the database. I used ORM framework in order to map beans to tables in our relational database in SQL Developer. Also, I worked with AWS and Jenkins. I would implement continuous integration with project collaborators such as Slack and Git.

IT COLLEGE ASSISTANT, QUEENS COLLEGE; FLUSHING, NY – 09/2013 - 11/2016 I was an employee of the Office of Information Technology at Queens College while being a full-time student. I provided supervision and maintenance of the open labs and surrounding classrooms. I helped with desk duties such as assistance with projectors, laptops, smart boards, and re-imaging computers.

## **EDUCATION**

QUEENS COLLEGE, FLUSHING, NY – COMPUTER SCIENCE, 2016
QUEENS COLLEGE, FLUSHING, NY – APPLIED MATHEMATICS, 2015

#### **SKILLS**

Java, Spring, Microservices, Hibernate, MySQL, Oracle SQL, ORM, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Angular, Bootstrap, Swift, Xcode, Project Management, Git, DevOps, Jenkins

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST